Guide to the Chauncey M. Depew papers, 1856-1934 MS2095
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Chauncey M. Depew papers
1856-1934
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Depew, Chauncey M. (Chauncey Mitchell)
MS2095
25 Linear Feet
Collection consists of fifty boxes of material documenting Chauncey M. Depew's career in public speaking from approximately 1880-1920. It features many published speeches, handwritten and typescript speeches, and notes, in addition to scrapbooks, memorial books, clippings, and photographs demonstrating Depew's prominence as an orator.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Chauncey M. Depew's widow May Palmer Depew donated this collection to The George Washington University in 1929.
Historical or Biographical Note
Chauncey Mitchell Depew (1834-1928) was a prominent railroad executive and U.S. Senator from New York and the namesake of the Chauncey M. Depew Professor of Communication at The George Washington University.
Depew was born in 1834 in Peekskill, New York. He attended Yale College, graduating in 1856 with high honors and was admitted to the bar. Depew first gained fame as an orator while campaigning for Abraham Lincoln in 1860. He then served in the New York State Assembly in 1862-63 as a Republican, and was elected Secretary of State in 1863, a position he held until 1865.
Depew became counsel for the New York Central Railroad in 1875, and later served as its vice president (1883) and president (1885). He resigned as president in 1898, at which time he became chairman of the board of directors of the Vanderbilt system of railroads.
In 1898, Depew was elected to the United States Senate as a Republican from New York and was reelected in 1905, serving until 1911. He was again nominated by the State legislature in 1912, but was defeated.
In 1871, Depew married Elise Ann Hegeman. They had one son, Chauncey Mitchell Depew, born 1879. Elise died in 1893 and Depew married May Palmer in 1901. They had no children.
Chauncey M. Depew died in 1928 in New York City.
After the death of her husband, May Palmer Depew donated $120,000 in 1929 to The George Washington University to establish a department of public speaking in her husband's memory. The Chauncey M. Depew Chair of Public Speaking was dedicated in January 1930; Professor Willard Hayes Yeager was the first appointed to that position. The endowed chair is now known as the Chauncey M. Depew Professor of Communication.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection consists of fifty boxes of material documenting Chauncey M. Depew's career in public speaking from approximately 1880-1920. It features many published speeches, handwritten and typescript speeches, and notes, in addition to scrapbooks, memorial books, clippings, and photographs demonstrating Depew's prominence as an orator and capturing public reaction to his death. In addition, correspondence in this collection includes letters from Mark Twain, Harry Houdini, John D. Rockefeller, William Vanderbilt, and many U.S. Presidents. In all, these materials provide insight into the politics and the communications techniques of the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries.
While the collection does contain a few letters from the Vanderbilts and some speeches about railroads and legislation, there are no records from Depew's tenure with the New York Central Railroad or from his terms in political office.
Collection Organization
Organized into nine series: Correspondence, Speeches and Articles, Scrapbooks, Memorial Books, Newspapers and Clippings, Photographs, Genealogical and Biographical Publications, Awards and Certificates, and Memorabilia.
Scrapbooks; Washington (D.C.); United States. Congress; Speeches; Public speaking; Photographs; Awards; Rogers, Will; Roosevelt, Theodore; Twain, Mark; Houdini, Harry
- Correspondence, 1839-1926; MS2095 Series 1; 1 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of two boxes of correspondence between Chauncey Depew and individuals from his personal and professional life. It includes a small number of letters sent by Depew from 1888 to 1923, but the majority of the correspondence is letters received by Depew.
  Other than some mail forwarded to Depew from 1839 and a few early letters, the bulk of the correspondence dates from 1886-1926.
  Among the correspondents represented in these files are most of the presidents of the United States of the late nineteenth and early twentieth century. Other notable correspondents include William Vanderbilt, Harry Houdini, Mark Twain, and John D. Rockefeller.
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 1)
    General note
  - Correspondence, Letters Sent (A-J), 1888-1923 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Letters Sent (K-Z), 1895-1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (A), 1894-1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (B), 1893-1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (C), 1889-1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (D), 1886-1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (E), 1886-1923 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (F), 1890-1920 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (G), 1887-1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (Hal-Har), 1888-1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (Hay-Hyde), 1890-1924 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (I-J), 1888-1923 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (K), 1910-1926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (L), 1897-1925 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (M), 1839-1921 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (N-O), 1880-1921 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (P), 1889-1926 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (R), 1865-1926 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (Roc-Rot), 1890-1926 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (S), 1865-1924 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (T), 1893-1911 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (U-V), 1871-1924; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Letters Received (W), 1888-1927; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Hegeman Family Letters (Hegeman Files), 1891; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Hegeman Family Letters (French Files), 1915; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Hegeman Family Letters (French Files), 1915; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Hegeman Family Letters (French Files), 1915; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Hegeman Family Letters (French Files), 1915; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Hegeman Family Letters (French Files), 1915; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Hegeman Family Letters (French Files), Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Speeches and articles, 1877-1927; MS2095 Series 2; 7 Linear feet (Box 10, Box 11, Box 8, Box 9, Box 6, Box 7, Box 4, Box 5, Box 16, Box 3, Box 15, Box 14, Box 13, Box 12)
  This series contains both published and unpublished speeches and articles written by Depew. Materials are arranged first by format (manuscripts; pamphlets; compilations; and speech fragments, notes and reference material) and then chronologically.
  Manuscripts include handwritten and typewritten speeches from 1877-1927. Speeches are listed by title when known, or by the first line when no title is identified. Many of these speeches were published and are also found in the Compilations.
  Pamphlets include individual speeches published as small pamphlets. They date from 1877-1910, though one is undated.
  Compilations consists of collections of speeches published in booklet and book form. These speeches date from 1890-1918.
  Speech fragments, notes and reference material contain portions of manuscripts and notes probably used for speeches. This material is mostly unidentifiable by date or event. If any date or event was given on the copy, that is noted; otherwise the first line identifies each copy. Some have numbered pages, while others do not. All are in folders as received at the time of processing. Most are undated.
  - Speeches and articles, undated (Box 3)
  - Manuscript, "Schiffheim's Life Insurance,", 12/22/1877 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript, "Yale Alumni Celebration of Athletic Victories,", 02/16/1884 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript, "Memorial to William Vanderbilt,", 1885 ca. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript, "Party and Politics in the British Isles," unidentified event, 03/15/1886 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript, "Union League Club Banquet Commemorating the Departure of Colored Troops for the Seat of War,", 03/16/1886 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript, "Army of the Potomac Oration,", 06/22/1887 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript, "George Washington Inauguration Centennial,", 04/30/1889 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript, "Yale Law School Anniversary,", 06/24/1889 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript, "Laying the Cornerstone of the YWCA Building," NYC, 12/02/1889 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The Evolution of the Puritan in Problem-Solving...,", 12/23/1889 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript, "Commencement of Industrial and Business Classes at the YWCA,", 05/28/1890 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript, "Introduction of Henry Morton Stanley, Metropolitan Opera House," NY, 11/11/1890 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript, "Parnell Memorial Exercises," Academy of Music, 11/15/1891 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript, "The Columbian Oration," The Columbian Exposition, 10/21/1892 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Manuscript, "The Adopted Son," New England Society, 12/22/1892 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Manuscript, "Turkish Outrages," St. Bartholomew's Church, NY, 12/30/1894 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript, "Patriotism and Education," Vanderbilt University, 06/18/1895 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Manuscript, "Introduction to Life of McKinley," Unidentified event, 06/26/1896 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Manuscript, "38th Anniversary of the Lincoln-Douglas Debate," Galesburg, IL, 10/07/1896 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Manuscript, "Press Club Dinner,", 12/14/1896 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Manuscript, "Practical Politics," University of Pennsylvania, 1896-1901 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Manuscript, "Nomination of Ashbel P. Fitch,", 09/28/1897 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "Bearing in mind these figures...,", 1898-1899 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Manuscript, "On the Death of Henry B. Hyde,", 05/05/1899 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Manuscript, "Resolution in Memory of Vice President Garret A. Hobart" (died 11/21/99), 01/10/1900 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Manuscript, "Philippine Speech to the Senate,", 02/27/1900 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Manuscript, "To the Senate on the Bill to Provide Puerto Rican Relief,", 03/28/1900 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Manuscript, "Birthday Celebration Dinner, Montauk Club of Brooklyn,", 04/21/1900 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Manuscript, "McKinley-Roosevelt Campaign Speech, the day before sailing to Europe,", 1900 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Manuscript, "Speech in favor of New York City for the Republican National Convention,", 12/15/1900 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Speeches and articles, undated (Box 4)
  - Manuscript, "4th of July Banquet, American Chamber of Commerce of Paris,", 1901 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript, "Impressions of London and Londoners in Coronation Year," unidentified event, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The most important development of the last twenty years...," The Financial News, London, New York Journal of Commerce, 12/03/1903 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "Practical Politics are largely taught by experience...," Yale Law School Political Club, New Haven, 05/24/1904 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "Our country has celebrated in the past few years many significant anniversaries." (50th Anniversary of the Republican Party, after 06/24), 1904 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The Democratic Convention which adjourned yesterday at Saratoga...," Afton, NY, (state convention), 1904 ca. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript, unknown location, "Republican State Convention,", 1908 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The problems which Congress had primarily to face...," (probably before Senate, concerning tariff bill), 1908-1909 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript, "To President Roosevelt and the Navy,", 02/28/1909 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript, "Appreciation of Marvin Hughitt, Director of the Vanderbilt Lines,", 10/28/1909 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript, "The Buffalo Evening News,", 09/02/1910 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript, "Ira Place Dinner,", 12/03/1910 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript, "The Tribune's New Year Greeting.", 1910 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript, "To the Calumet Club," ("maybe 11/14"), 1910 ca. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Manuscript, "Before the Pilgrim Society,", 1910 ca. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "Your inquiry, 'How in retiring from active public service...,'", 1910 ca. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript, "Twenty-third Annual Dinner at the Montauk Club in celebration of Depew's 80th Birthday,", 04/25/1914 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Manuscript, "The Return of Roosevelt," unidentified event, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Manuscript, "Campaign speech for Hughes Running Against Wilson,", 1916 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Manuscript, "A Celebration of Securing Permanent Light for the Statue of Liberty," given by the New York World, Waldorf-Astoria, NY, 12/02/1916 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Manuscript, "Pilgrim Society Dinner for Joseph H. Choate on his Eighty-fifth Birthday," Union League Club, NY, 01/27/1917 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Manuscript, "To the Drafted Men of Tarrytown, NY Who Were Leaving for Camp,", 09/10/1917 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "1917 will live through the ages...,", 1917-1918 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Manuscript, "We Must See This Through,", 1917-1918 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Manuscript, "Tribute to the Memory of Dr. Charles E. Fitch,", 01/15/1918 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Manuscript, "4th of July," The London Times, 1918 ca. (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Manuscript, "Biographical Sketch of Frank Hiscock,", 10/24/1919 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Manuscript, "Christmas Message,", 12/1919 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Manuscript, "Memorial to Roosevelt,", 1919 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "I am sorry that it is not possible for me to be with you...,", 1919 ca. (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Manuscript, "Upon the Reminiscences of a Lifetime,", 1921 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Manuscript, "On the Progress of Civilization Through Invention," ("mostly Edison, possibly radio address") New Year's 1921 or 1922, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Manuscript, "Foreword to the Depew Autobiography,", 1922 ca. (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The World is right and wise in advocating New York...," New York World article, 07/16/1923 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Manuscript, "The Decline of Extempore Oratory,", 11/01/1923 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Manuscript, "Reminiscences of St. Augustine," St. Augustine, Florida, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "This is the birthday of the Marquis de Lafayette...,", 1923 ca. (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "When I was a young man living in the country...," (concerning education for women), 1924 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Manuscript, "In Memory of Alfred H. Smith, President of the New York Central Railroad,", 1924 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Manuscript, "4th of July," Hot Springs, VA, 07/04/1925 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The first quarter of each century...,", 1925 ca. (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Manuscript, "St. Augustine Historical Society," St. Augustine, Florida, 03/1926 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Manuscript, "Thirty-fifth Annual Dinner at the Montauk Club, in Celebration of Depew's 92nd Birthday," NY, 04/1926 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Manuscript, "Statement for the United States Historical Society,", 12/26/1926 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "It is a very interesting and suggestive thought...," (100 years of New York Central Railroad, penciled date "1922"), 1926 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Manuscript, "150th Anniversary of the Declaration of Independence,", 1926 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "As people gathered in communities...," (concerning the 150th Anniversary of the Declaration of Independence), 1926 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Manuscript, "Pilgrim Society Dinner for the Earl of Reading, Viceroy of India,", 1926-1927 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Manuscript, "Annual Meeting of the St. Augustine Historical Society," St. Augustine, Florida, 03/01/1927 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Manuscript, "4th of July, 151st Anniversary of the Declaration of Independence,", 1927 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "We are witnesses and participants...,", undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "There have been efforts...," (concerning bills supported and passed), undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "It was a critical period of the Civil War...,", undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The most noticeable change in Europe since last year...,", undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "To call an extra session of Congress...," (concerning economic conditions), undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The adjustment of the world to the adoption...,", undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "I am much interested in the story of Governor Cox [sic]...," (concerning campaign and Governor Dix), undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Manuscript, "Nomination of George R. Sheldon for Lieutenant Governor,", undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Manuscript, "100th or 200th Anniversary of the Founding of the Old New England Churches," unidentified event, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Manuscript, "Dedication of a Bridge named for Alfred Holland Smith,", undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Manuscript, "Campaign Speech for O'Dell and Higgins for Governor and Lieutenant Governor,", undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "If one lives long enough his span of life embraces...,", undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Speeches and articles, undated (Box 5)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "Society is a term of as wide a range as civilization.", undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "It is an anomalous situation...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript, "Memorial to Col. Schoonmaker,", undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "It is the duty of every man to fit himself for citizenship...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "Macauley made a gruesome prophecy...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "A veteran observer who had lived through several critical periods..,", undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "We can best bid farewell to the old year...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The time has arrived when the Republican Party...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The committee has assigned to me as a subject reminiscences...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "I have faced a greater variety of conditions...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "I feel that I am here tonight under a spirit of false pretense...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The most remarkable revolution in the last fifty years...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "Mr. President and Republican Editors - Our canvass this Fall...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "A veteran on the platform is inclined to indulge...," (campaign speech for Hughes?), undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Manuscript, untitled, " I fell seriously alarmed when Colonel Wright...," (concerning schools and Peekskill Academy), undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "Law is a jealous mistress and no lawyer can continue...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "In no country in the world...," (concerning "British love for the Sovereigns"), undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "In the last ten years about fourteen millions of immigrants have entered...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Manuscript, "Memorial to David Kimball," (38 year employee of NYCC?), undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The colleges for girls have been made possible...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "When you met in special session...," ("Probably draft of a speech made on floor or before a committee of NY Senate" concerning revenue), undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Manuscript, "Preface to Mr. Henry Alloway's Book on Wall Street,", undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Manuscript, "Memorial to Dr. W. Seward Webb," (director of the NYCRR), undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Manuscript, "Answer of Mr. Depew to interviewer's question, 'What was the most severe punishment you ever suffered in your youth?'", undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Manuscript, "Memorial to William C. Brown," (former company president), undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Manuscript, "Memorial to Alfred H. Smith," (President of the NYCRR), undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The seventy-five years just closed have been so crowded with marvels...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The end and aim of human aspiration and ambition is to attain happiness...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Manuscript, "Memorial to General Horace Porter," Union League Club, NY, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The story which is told in Mr. Lurie's Article...", undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "I asked the proprietor of a newspaper abroad...", undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The Doctor's greatest delight..." (concerning his connection with the railroad), undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "It affords me great pleasure...," (concerning the Railroad Branch, YMCA), undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "It is always a privilege to be an American citizen...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Manuscript, untitled, "The familiar headlines in the daily paper were...,", undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Speeches and articles, undated (Box 6)
  - Pamphlet, "Centennial Celebration of the Formation of the State Government," Kingston, NY, 07/30/1877 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlet, "Argument in opposition to an Act to Create a Board of Railroad Commissioners," NY State Assembly, 03/28/1878 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlet, "Argument re: State and Railroads, Special Investigating Committee," New York State Assembly, 11/28/1879-11/29/1879 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlet, "Address at the Unveiling of the Statue of Alexander Hamilton," Central Park, NY, 11/22/1880 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlet, "Argument in opposition to the Bills providing for the Creation of a Board of Railroad Commissioners," NY Assembly Committee, 03/16/1881 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlet, "Argument against the Anti-Freight Discrimination Bills," Assembly Railroad Committee, 03/09/1882 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlet, "Address Before the Annual Convention of the Psi Upsilon Societies of the Various Colleges in the United States," Syracuse, NY, 05/10/1882 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlet, "Address Before the Graduating Class of the Columbia College Law School," Academy of Music, NY, 05/17/1882 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Pamphlet, "Oration at the Unveiling of the Bartholdi Statue of Liberty Enlightening the World,", 10/28/1886 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlet, "Oration at the Reunion of The Army of the Potomac," Saratoga, 06/22/1887 (Box 6, Folder 10)